# Syed Hassan

35 Charles St. West Toronto, M4Y 1R6 647-410-5790 syed.ext@gmail.com

### **Professional Profile**

Emerging software developer with proficiency in programming languages essential for creating web apps from start to finish. Well-trained in creating responsive web designs. Passionate about enhancing the user experience of digital products. Love to solve human problems using machines.

### Education

#### **Bachelor of Information**

2024

Faculty of Information, University of Toronto

(expected)

Representative Courses: Information Design Studio, Integrative Approaches to Technology, How to Make a Compute and Why,

Computational Reasoning, Worlds Become Data.

### Diploma of Multimedia Design and Development

2022

Faculty of Media Arts, Humber College

Representative Courses: UI Design, Multimedia Design, Creative Thinking,
Creative Coding, Web Technology, Contemporary
Web Design, Emerging Multimedia Practice.

Bachelor of Arts 2015

Faculty of Hadith, Abu Bakr Islamic University

### Certificates - Accounting & Finance: ACCA Part 1 and CAT

2011

Tabani's School of Accountancy, Karachi, Pakistan

### **Selected Projects**

### **Full-Stack CMS Website with APIs**

2022

Course Project (Contemporary Web Design II) [available]

- Programmed a Content Management System with REST API.
- Integrated Spotify's API to browse and save artists.
- Made the site capable of exporting data for others to use from our API.

### **Responsive Website Design**

2022

Club Cricket of Chicago, USA [available]

- Created a modern responsive website for an emerging cricket club.
- Constructed a solid and scalable program structure using React JS.
- Coded creative web animations to enhance the experience.

### **Mobile App Mock-up**

2022

Course Project (Multimedia Design II) [available]

- Conducted user research and competitor analysis.
- Used design thinking concepts and usability heuristics.
- Created an interactive mobile app mock-up using Adobe XD.
- Conducted usability testing and sought user feedback.

### **Professional Experience**

### **Designer and Developer**

2020 - present

Freelance

- Creating single and multipage responsive websites.
- Designing brand elements and packages.
- Front-End Development.
- API's and back-end development.

### **Data Supervisor**

2021 - present

Metro Inc., Toronto

- Managing the warehouse's Content Management System.
- Running and manipulating macros and VBA scripts.

### Additional Experience

#### Administration and VAT Controller

2017 - 2019

Cool and Cool Middle East, Dubai, UAE

#### Administration and Finance Coordinator

2010 - 2016

Palm Group of Companies, Karachi, Pakistan

## Selected Papers & Articles

Hassan, S. (2022). Exploring Animations for Websites. Course Article – Emerging Multimedia Practice II. [available]

Hassan, S. (2022). Unlocking the Design Process. Course Article - Information Design Studio I. [available]

Hassan, S. (2022). Tech Demo Profile - The Metaverse. Course Essay - Information in Cultural Imagination. [available]

Hassan, S. (2023). Exploring Subway Delays – TTC 2022. Data Analysis – Worlds Become Data. [available]

### Certifications

### **LinkedIn Learning Path**

2021 Become a Front-End Developer 2021 Become a Web Developer 2021 Learn CSS (in progress) Become a React Developer (in progress) Become a Full-Stack Developer

### Skills & Qualifications

Usability Testing and Design Critique

Design Thinking React JS JavaScript

User Research CSS & SCSS jQuery, Bootstrap, Tailwind

**CSS Animations** Human Centered Approach HTML & XML Responsive Web Design HTML Canvas PHP Version control using Git and GitHub SQL GreenSock JS Python WordPress

Sketching, Wireframing and Prototyping

C++ Animation and Motion Graphics Express JS (novice)

R

Adobe Creative Suite Visual Storytelling NoSQL, MongoDB (novice)

Agile Workflow Figma AWS EC2 (novice)

Microsoft Office Critical Thinking

SAP **Problem Solving** 

portfolio: sai-yed.com

Node JS (novice)